RG 004:066, Harwinton Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Harwinton Probate Court records
1830-2010
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Harwinton District)
22 cubic feet
Record books, 1835-1947; Probate files, 1835-1976; Wills, circa 1830-2010.
RG004_066
1930-002, 2011-008 and 2012-042.
Historical Note
Harwinton, Litchfield County, Town established in October 1737
The Harwinton Probate District was constituted May 27, 1835, from the Litchfield Probate District. The Harwinton Probate District merged with the Litchfield, Northwest Corner, and Thomaston Probate Districts on January 5, 2011, to create the Litchfield Hills Probate District. The Litchfield Hills Probate District serves the municipalities of Canaan, Cornwall, Harwinton, Kent, Litchfield, Morris, Norfolk, North Canaan, Salisbury, Sharon, Thomaston, and Warren.
Town of Harwinton, Probate District chronology:
October 1739 - October 1742, Hartford District
October 1742 - May 26, 1835, Litchfield District
May 27, 1835 - January 4, 2011, Harwinton District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Litchfield Hills District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-10, 1835-1967. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 10. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1835-1976. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1835-1924 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Wills, circa 1830-2010.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 10.
Probate files are arranged by accession. Each accession is arranged alphabetically.
Wills are arranged alphabetically.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1930-002 are represented in this index.
Probate Files: The History and Genealogy reference staff has access to an index for the probate files in accession 2011-008 and wills in accession 2012-042.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut - Harwinton
Places:
Harwinton (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Probate files from 1921-1976 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Adoptions (all documents) from January 1, 1944 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Removals of parent as guardian of minor (all documents) and terminations of parental rights (all documents) from October 1, 1975 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §45a-754. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
Accession 2011-008, Record books, 1835-1967, and Probate files, 1925-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-2, 4-5, 7, 1835-1924; probate files 1836-1915 (Accession 1930-002 only); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1930-002 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): March 17, 1930 (1835-1908); October 10, 1935 (1865-1924). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence.
The record books and probate files in accession 2011-008 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on July 28, 2010.
The wills in accession 2012-042 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on May 17, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1835-1967; 6 cubic feet (10 volumes); 2011-008
  - Records, 1835-1854 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1854-1880 (Volume 2)
  - Orders and decrees, 1874-1902 (Volume 3)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1880-1907 (Volume 4)
  - Bonds and wills, 1881-1940 (Volume 5)
  - Orders and decrees, 1901-1923 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1907-1922 (Volume 7)
    On spine: "Miscellaneous"
  - Orders and decrees, 1921-1948 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1924-1936 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1936-1947 (Volume 10)
- Probate files, 1835-1924; 5 cubic feet; 1930-002
  - Abbott - Baker (Drawer 1)
  - Balch - Barber, O. (Drawer 2)
  - Barber, P. - Brown (Drawer 3)
  - Bryant - Carroll (Drawer 4)
  - Casser - Churchill, C. (Drawer 5)
  - Churchill, D. - Denzo (Drawer 6)
  - Dibell - Goodsell (Drawer 7)
  - Goodwin - Hopkins (Drawer 8)
  - Hotchkiss - Lang (Drawer 9)
  - Leach - Nichols (Drawer 10)
  - Noble - Potter, D. (Drawer 11)
  - Potter, E. - Scoville, B. (Drawer 12)
  - Scoville, C. - Tomi (Drawer 13)
  - Tremp - Wilson, D. (Drawer 14)
  - Wilson, E. - Zucco (Drawer 15)
- Inventory Control Book, 1835-1924; T003073
  Index of the two accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1930-002
  Also known as the Godard Digest
- Probate files, 1925-1976; 9 cubic feet; 2011-008
  - Barker - Carotenuti (Box 1)
  - Carpenter - Cser (Box 2)
  - Curtiss - Frost, G. (Box 3)
  - Frost, R. - Hudak (Box 4)
  - Hungerford - Lane (Box 5)
  - Lascko - Peterson (Box 6)
  - Petosa - Schling (Box 7)
  - Schmitt - Truskauskas (Box 8)
  - Turner - Zwick (Box 9)
- Wills, circa 1830-2010; 2 cubic feet; 2012-042
  - A - P (Box 1)
  - Q - Z (Box 2)